let set31=
[
    {
        question:`#1. Regarding the Chemical reactions, consider the following statements:  \n 1. New atoms are produced in a chemical reaction.  \n 2. Exothermic reactions are accompanied by absorption of Heat  \n Which of the statements given above is/are correct? `,
        options:
        [
'A. 1 only ',
'B. 2 only ',
'C. Both 1 and 2 ',
            'D. Neither 1 nor 2 ',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: D`,
        exp:`Explanation: During a chemical reaction atoms of one element do not change into those of another element. Nor do atoms disappear from the mixture or appear from elsewhere, in fact chemical reactions involve the breaking and making of bonds between atoms to produce new substances. Exothermic reactions are accompanied by release of Heat. `
    },
    {
        question:`#2. Which of the following best defines the oxidation of any substance? `,
        options:
        [
'A. Gain in oxygen ',
'B. Loss in oxygen  ',
'C. Gain in hydrogen ',
            'D. Loss in hydrogen ',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: A`,
        exp:`Explanation: If a substance gains oxygen during a reaction, it is said to be oxidised. If a substance loses oxygen during a reaction, it is said to be reduced. If in a reaction, one reactant gets oxidised while the other gets reduced, it is called oxidation-reduction reactions or redox reactions. `
    },
    {
        question:`#3. Regarding the oxidation, consider the following statements: \n 1. The Black coating on silver and the green coating on copper are examples of Corrosion. \n 2. Bags of chips are flushed with gas such as nitrogen to prevent the chips from getting oxidised. \n Which of the statements given above is/are correct? `,
        options:
        [
'A. 1 only ',
'B. 2 only ',
'C. Both 1 and 2 ',
            'D. Neither 1 nor 2  ',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: C`,
        exp:`Explanation: When a metal is attacked by substances around it such as moisture, acids, etc., it is said to be corroded and this process is called corrosion. The black coating on silver and the green coating on copper are examples of corrosion. Corrosion causes damage to car bodies, bridges, iron railings, ships and to all objects made up of metals, especially those of iron. When fats and oils are oxidised, they become rancid and their smell and taste change. Usually substances which prevent oxidation (antioxidants) are added to foods containing fats and oil. Keeping food in air tight containers helps to slow down oxidation. Due to this reason, bags of chips are flushed with gas such as nitrogen to prevent the chips from getting oxidised. `
    },
    {
        question:`#4. Regarding the lime, consider the following statements: \n 1. Calcium hydroxide is also called as quicklime. \n 2. Calcium hydroxide reacts slowly with the carbon dioxide in air to form a thin layer of calcium carbonate on the walls after two to three days of whitewashing. \n Which of the statements given above is/are correct? `,
        options:
        [
'A. 1 only ',
'B. 2 only  ',
'C. Both 1 and 2 ',
            'D. Neither 1 nor 2 ',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: B`,
        exp:`Explanation: Calcium oxide is called as quicklime. Calcium oxide reacts vigorously with water to produce slaked lime (calcium hydroxide) releasing a large amount of heat. Calcium hydroxide reacts slowly with the carbon dioxide in air to form a thin layer of calcium carbonate on the walls. Calcium carbonate is formed after two to three days of white washing and gives a shiny finish to the walls. `
    },
    {
        question:`#5. Respiration is the type of which of the following reactions? `,
        options:
        [
'A. Combination reaction ',
'B. Decomposition reaction ',
'C. Exothermic reaction ',
            'D. Endothermic reaction ',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: C`,
        exp:`Explanation: Respiration is an exothermic process. Reactions in which heat is released along with the formation of products are called exothermic chemical reactions. As we all know, we need energy to stay alive. We get this energy from the food we eat. During digestion, food is broken down into simpler substances. For  example, rice, potatoes and bread contain carbohydrates. These carbohydrates are broken down to form glucose. This glucose combines with oxygen in the cells of our body and provides energy. `
    },
    {
        question:`#6. The neutralization reaction between an acid and a base is a type of: `,
        options:
        [
'A. Double displacement reaction ',
'B. Displacement reaction ',
'C. Addition reaction ',
            'D. Decomposition reaction ',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: A`,
        exp:`Explanation: A double displacement reaction is a type of reaction in which two reactants exchange ions to form two new compounds. Double displacement reactions typically result in the formation of a product that is a precipitate. Double displacement reactions take the form: AB + CD â†’ AD + CB Key Takeaways: Double Displacement Reaction 1. A double displacement reaction is a type of chemical reaction in which the reactant ions exchange places to form new products.  2. Usually, a double displacement reaction results in precipitate formation. 3. The chemical bonds between the reactants may be either covalent or ionic. 4. A double displacement reaction is also called a double replacement reaction, salt metathesis reaction, or double decomposition. The reaction occurs most often between ionic compounds, although technically the bonds formed between the chemical species may be either ionic or covalent in nature. Acids or bases also participate in double displacement reactions. The bonds formed in the product compounds are the same type of bonds as seen in the reactant molecules. Usually, the solvent for this type of reaction is water. `
    },
    {
        question:`#6. The end product of an alcoholic fermentation is:`,
        options:
        [
'A). pyrubic acid',
'B). acetaldehyde',
'C). ethyl alcohol',
            'D). formic acid',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: C`,
        exp:`Explanation: Alcoholic fermentation is called as lactic acid fermentation, it is anaerobic respiration that does not require oxygen. It is the process of release of energy by incomplete degradation of organic food hence end products are never fully inorganic. First glycolysis occurs and forms two molecules of pyruvate after that fermentation occurs, no oxygen involved and later forms ethyl alcohol and lactic acid. So, the correct option is ' ethanol or lactic acid'.`
    },
    {
        question:`#8. Which of the following gases is used in the storage of fat and oil containing foods for a long time? `,
        options:
        [
'A. Carbondioxide gas ',
'B. Nitrogen gas ',
'C. Oxygen gas ',
            'D. Neon gas ',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: B`,
        exp:`Explanation: Helium or nitrogen both can be used for storage of fresh sample of an oil for a long time. These gases are called inert gases as they do not react with most elements including oxygen.  Thus these gases create an inert environment for the oil and prevent its reaction with any element in the environment that prevent from getting it rancid. `
    },
    {
        question:`#9. The respiration process during which glucose undergoes slow combustion by combining with oxygen in the cells of our body to produce energy, is a kind of: `,
        options:
        [
'A. Exothermic process ',
'B. Endothermic process ',
'C. Reversible process ',
            'D. Physical process ',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: A `,
        exp:`Explanation A`
    },
    {
        question:`#10. A chemical reaction does not involve: `,
        options:
        [
'A. Formation of new substances having entirely different properties that of the reactants ',
'B. Breaking of old chemical bonds and formation of new chemical bonds ',
'C. Rearrangement of the atoms of reactants to form new products ',
            'D. Changing of the atoms of on element into those of another element to form new products  ',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: D `,
        exp:`Explanation D`
    }
]